うるさいぐらいで ちょうどいい
雲の中に隠れないで
私の心に突き刺して
怖いのは私のほう
私の上へ落ちてきて
目の覚めるような稲妻を
木１本とないこの平地で
私に逃げ場はないのだから
ずいぶん遠くに落ちたみたいだ
平地の避雷針は
“聞こえなかった”と首をふる
消え入りそうで 後付けのような雷鳴を
目覚めのキッスはまどろむあなたに
あやかしリップなお姫様
時間がないの いま何時？
授業開始の５分前
出会いの切符は夢見るあなたに
まやかしVIPなエア・フォース
急いでないの いま大事
あなたに出会う５分前
Lightning crashing in the distance.
ヴィーナスお隣さんなの どうして？
知らない間に
The faint, insignificant sound of thunder.
ジーザスお向かいさんなの
聞いてやばいの
A lightning rod on a plain.
It sways without a sound.
大胆あいつの攻撃
バイバイ気づいてない振り
大胆あいつの衝撃 まさに生き地獄
Don't hide away in the clouds.
寝起きのキックは挨拶代わりに
生足いっつも傷だらけ
Appear above my head.
Strike me.
手持ちのチップをあの子に賭けたら
まばたきみっつでノック・ダウン
Be as loud as you can.
嫌いじゃないの 嫌なだけ
予測出来ないこの気持ち
The awakening lightning...
期待しないで 暇なだけ
あなたと消える５分間
Come, pierce my heart.
ヴィーナスあの子はいつでもそうなの？
いまなら間に合う
It's me who's scared.
ジーザス引き返せないの 早く気付いて
There's nowhere to hide on this flat, empty land.
Chapter 95: "Wish Upon a Star"
お前は本当にいい加減さ やんのか
やんねえのか はっきりしてくんねえ？
Hey, could you hurry up and decide
if you're gonna do it or not?
You made such a big deal out of it.
あんだけ引っ張っといて
とんだ鳥肉野郎じゃのう！
You're some kinda damn chicken, aren't ya?
ふああー！
Rec's a wimp!
リクさんのヘタレ！
リクさんのロートル！
Rec's useless!
I'm sorry—my hand acted on its own! I'm sorry!
すいません！
手が勝手にやったんです ごめんなさい！
完全にお父さんが
トラウマになっているみたいだね
It seems your dad really did a number on you.
うん 精神的外傷を克服するのは
たやすくないからな
Traumatizing someone like that is no easy task.
That sounds like a sad excuse
from a weak man to me.
脆弱な男の言い訳にしか聞こえないわね
I dunno what your sad sack story is, but how
can a grown man still be afraid of his dad?
だいたいよう
どんな事情があるか知らねえけどよう
いい年こいて
親父がこえーってなんなのよ
If you were a real Japanese man,
you'd just get over it already!
日本男児なら
男 見せたらんかい こらぁ！
うわぁ！ 大きくならないでぇ
Don't get any bigger!
Enough!
いいじゃないか
Everyone is scared of something.
怖いものくらい誰にだってある！
Nino...
ニノさん…
It's okay, Rec. You can be
scared of ghosts, or bugs,
いいんだ リク
ひいー！
おばけと虫と
ピーマン無理です
I can't stand bell peppers.
or bell peppers, or your dad!
ピーマンとお父さんが怖いくらい
Everyone is—
誰だって…
How old do you think he is?!
何歳児の怖いものだよ！
だ 大丈夫です ニノさん
後で必ず電話を…
It's okay, Nino. I'll definitely call him later!
Hah! As if.
はあー！ ないなーい
You're just gonna keep on
dragging your stupid heels.
お前 そうやって延び延びのまま
終わるつもりなんだろ
Wha— Says who?
ああっ 誰が！
C'mon, Nino. Leave this loser in the dust.
なあ ニノ
こんなヘナチョコじゃなくてよ
You're supposed to make your wish on a star.
昔からお願い事は
お星様にって決まってるんだぜ
So come on! Wish upon your star!
さあさあ 星に願いを
おお そうなのか
Whoa, are you serious?
Don't be stupid! You can't just—
ふざけんなよ 無責任な！
そんな気休めじゃ…
Aww, my lovely Hoshi...
まあ 星くんたら
You're so sweet and romantic.
優しくてロマンチストなのね
Yup! I'm not just—
まあな これぐらい
But I thought
でも確か… 願い事っていうのは
we're supposed to make a wish on a
shooting star, specifically. Right?
流れ星にするものだったわよね
All right. Go ahead and shoot.
さっ 流れて
いい？ ニノちゃん
Nino, you have to repeat your wish three
times while the star's shooting, okay?
流れ星が流れている間に
お願い事３回唱えるのよ
Got it!
心得た！
Wai— Isn't this more like...
ちょ な 流れっていうか
これ飛び降りでしょ？
falling?
はははは ははー！
さすが星 言うだけあるな
Way to go! Hoshi—always a man of his word.
この！
You!
Hey, come on.
ほーらほら お前 怖いもんねえんだろ
You're not scared, are you?
最悪だな お前
You're a real asshole.
Show me what it means to be a man, Hoshi.
さあ 男を見せてくれよ 星
What's your deal? You're enjoying this too much!
なんだ てめえ 急に元気にー
You look great!
まあ 似合うっ
What—
これは…
Two is better than one.
１つより ２つ
It's always better to have more stars, right?
希望の星は多いほうが素敵でしょ？
えっ そりゃそうだよな
She's right! What's wrong, Rec?
You scared of heights or something?
おやぁ どうしたの？ リクくん
もしかして高いところも怖いのかなー？
な ふざけんなよ！ 俺はなあ
Not a chance! I've—
もう２度も
ここから落ちてるんだからなあ
I've already fallen off here twice before.
Is that really something to be proud of?
まあ自慢できる事ではないわね
Then why don't you do it
a third time? If you dare!
だったら３回目
Youがcanならdoしちゃいなよ
No, you should go first.
You're the professional star, after all!
いや それなら お前からだろ？
現職 お星様なんだから
Or what? Are you scared?
それとも何？ やっぱり怖いんだろ
ふはははっ こんなの
ジェットコースターみたいなもんよ
This is just like a rollercoaster!
Plus, if it's for Nino—
それにニノを思えば これぐらい
Love!
愛 だからな
Ya dig?
はははははっ だったら俺は
六本木ヒルズから飛び降りられるぜ
Then I'd jump off Roppongi Hills for her!
Well I'd jump from the metropolitan office!
じゃあ俺は都庁から飛ぶねー！
じゃあ俺は東京タワーからー！
Then I'd jump from Tokyo Tower!
ふっ いいから…
Whatever...
Just do it, already!
おいきなさい
Ah, they're like cute little Geminis.
まあっ かわいい双子星
わあー
Hurry! Make a wish!
じゃっ 早く早く 願い事を
Please let us stay here forever!
ここにずっと
みんなでいられますように
Please let us stay here forever!
ここにずっと
みんなでいられますように
Please let us stay here forever!
ここにずっと
みんなでいられますように
Wha—
ど どういう事だ？
What did you say?
The Arakawa Development Project
has been... shut down?
河川敷再開発プロジェクトが
中止というのは！
Their wish has come true.
願いが叶いました
Chapter 96: "Changes"
How could you?
なぜ中止などに？
I'm deeply sorry, but—
いえ 本当に申し訳ないと思いますが
んんっ 申し訳ないで済む話だと
思っているのかね
You think a simple apology will do?
Explain yourself. My company just won
the development rights today!
説明したまえ
今日のコンペは事前の話し合いで
結果も決定していた
We're only one step away from
beginning construction!
あとは工事というところまで
進んでいたんだぞ
Connecting...
Listen, yelling at me won't help anything.
いやあ そんなこと僕に言われても…
What?! Where's the Minister?
なんだと 大臣はどこにいるんだ？
He's in a meeting—
大臣なら会議中で
いつ終わる？
When's it over?!
Mee-tings-for-ev-er!
一 生 会 議 中…！
Actually, I've been instructed not to
forward your calls to him anymore.
実は市ノ宮様からのお電話は
お取り次ぎするなと言われております
どあっ
What?
なんだと？ ふざけるな！ 私を誰だと…
Don't be ridiculous! Who do
you think you're talking to?!
Who do you think funds all your little pet proj—
貴様らの資金は
どこから出ているか分かって…
さあ僕 電話番なんで分からないです
How should I know? I just answer the phone.
There's really nothing more to
say, so if you'll excuse me.
とにかく もうお話しできることはないので
失礼しまーす
That was amazing.
えっ すごいね君
大臣 あれでよかったんですか？
Are you sure this is okay, though?
It's fine.
ああ いいんだ
資金を断つとか言ってましたけど…
He might really cut our funding, you know.
Don't worry about it.
おお 大丈夫
I'll handle it from here. Thanks a bunch.
今日からは俺が流す ありがとさん
Sorry for bothering you.
邪魔したな
Who was that just now?
I've never seen him before.
今の誰ですか？ 見ない人ですけど
You're better off not knowing.
知らんほうがよかろうよ
なぜだ！
How?!
Talking to me like that!
この私をこの扱い！
なぜこの計画が消える？
How could my plan fail?
The government couldn't care
less about that speck of land.
こんな場所どうなろうと
国の連中にはどうでもいいはずだ
So what happened?
一体何が？
Could it be?
まさか…
んっ 市ノ宮様 どうなさいました？
Mr. Ichinomiya!
What's going on?
I have the weekly report on Ko.
今週の行様の報告を
Not now! I'm going out for a while.
いらん 少し出かける
出かけるって今から会議では？
Out? You have a meeting soon.
Where exactly are you going?
What about the report?
一体どちらに？ それに報告はいつ…
The report...
報告なら今から行く河川敷で直接聞こう
I'll just go see for myself!
Around that time, near the river...
その頃 河川敷では…
That's it!
さあ
Again!
何度でも
Go!
おいきなさい
World domination, world domination,
world domination!
世界掌握 世界掌握 世界掌握
両想い 両想い 両想い
Love me back, love me back, love me back!
White line, white line, white line!
白線 白線 白線
Lab explosion, lab explosion, lab explosion!
研究所爆破 研究所爆破 研究所爆破
Venus, Venus, Venus.
金星 金星 金星
Bleeding, sweaty shooting stars continue to fall.
血と汗のにじむ流星群が降り続けていた
What did you do?
一体どんな手を使った？
What kind of power did you leverage?
お前に一体何の力があったというのだ？
I won't allow it!
絶対に認めんぞ
そう
たとえこの身に何が起ころうとも
No matter—
No matter what happens to this body!
An
Un
bound
Chapter 97: "An Unbound Man's Father"
...   's  Father
How unexpected.
予想外だった
How could I have imagined a gang of eccentric
youths would sweep in and steal my pants?
まさか橋に降り立った瞬間に
エキセントリックな子供たちによって
ズボンを奪われるなどと
How humiliating!
なんという屈辱…
何故だ？
Why?
Could this be another of Ko's traps?
これはもしや行の仕掛けた罠？
How far will he go to insult me?
あいつめ どこまで私をコケに
しかし これしきで動じる私ではない
However, I'm far better than this!
Putting my pants up so high—
あんな所にズボンをかけ
Did he really think I'd climb
up there to retrieve them?
私が取りに行く事を
期待しているのだろうが
I can just pretend this is the cool-biz style.
これしきクールビズと割り切れば
うん？
釣り竿？
A fishing pole?
Hey.
なあ
これ… お前のだろ？
Are these yours?
You look like you're missing something
on your lower half there.
下半身のパーツが
足りてないように見えるんだが
That's Ko's—
この少女 確か行の
Your butt's gonna freeze off.
Hurry up and put 'em on.
ケツ冷やすぞ 早くはけ
I decline.
断る
Those do indeed belong to me. But accepting
them from you would go against my family motto.
いかにもそれは私のものだが
それを受け取ることは我が家訓に反する
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
t
o
a
n
y
o
n
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
t
o
a
n
y
o
n
e
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
t
o
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
t
o
N
e
v
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
N
e
v
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
n
e
!
N
e
v
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
n
!
N
e
v
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
"Never be indebted to anyone!"
他人に借りを作るべからず
It's our strictest rule, stitched into a tie worn
by the eldest son of each generation!
一族長男が締める家宝のネクタイに
縫い込まれているこの家訓にな
e
v
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
t
e
v
r
b
e
i
n
d
e
b
t
e
d
t
As the head of the family, I also have
it embroidered on my undies!
家長の私に至っては
パンツにすら縫い込んでいるのだよ
ちなみにこれは
めったに見られるものではないぞ 君
You won't get to see these very often, you know.
なんか知らんが うれしそうで何よりだ
I dunno what's going on, but I'm
glad you're happy about it.
But you know, the way you look and that
stuff you said reminds me of my lover.
しかしお前 見た感じも言う事も
私の恋人に似ているな
I've no name to give.
名乗る必要はない
Actually, you're exactly like he
was when I first met him.
というより会ったばかりの頃のあいつか
名乗る必要はない
I have no name to give her.
I'd hoped to never have to meet her.
できれば一度も会わずに
済ませたいと思っていたのだ
But seeing her up close,
しかし こうして見ると…
She does remind me quite a bit of... her.
少しだけあの人に似ている気もするか
Hey, can you hear me?
おい 聞いてるか？
Of course.
もちろんだ
He would throw a tantrum any time I brought
him food. Something about returning favors.
あいつもな 会ったばかりの頃にな
ご飯を持ってってやるたびに
お礼だ何だとうるさかったんだ
That's only natural.
それは当然だろう
君も何か要求すべきだ 公平でない
It's only fair that you should
demand something in return.
It's already fair.
公平だぞ
When he's all stuffed and satisfied,
あいつがお腹いっぱいになると
I feel satisfied, too.
私もお腹いっぱいになったみたいな
感じになるんだ
そうだ
Oh, that's right.
最近あいつ
私たちのためにすごく働いてるから
今日はたくさん捕ってってやるか
Working? What kind of work?
ほう それはどんな働きだね？
I may as well gather some
information while I'm here.
どうせだ
行に会う前に情報収集していくか
Actually... we're getting kicked out of our homes.
実は私たちは
家から追い出されそうになっていてな
And he's trying to stop it.
それを止めようとしているんだ
He's sacrificed his entire body.
今なんて体を張って
What does she mean? She talks
as if they're still in trouble.
どういう事だ？
まるでまだ 問題が
解決されていないような言いぐさ
Look. You can see him from here.
ほら ここからでも
私の恋人の頑張っいてるところが
見れるんだぞ
My lover's doing everything he can for us.
今ここで？
Here? Now?
一体あいつは何…
What's he trying to—
He became a star to try and make
all our wishes come true.
自らが一番星になることで
みんなの願いを体を張って叶える
Look at the image of my lover's bravery!
私の恋人の勇姿だ！
Are you sure you don't need glasses?
君 視力は大丈夫かね？
Chapter 98: "Fatherly Love"
Well, the real stars will start
coming out pretty soon.
さ そろそろ
本物のお星様が出るころだから
I think it's time to put away these pseudo-stars.
偽物はさっさとしまっちゃいましょうね
So what was the point of that?
Why was I hanging from a rope?
じゃあ何で 偽物なのに
何で俺ぶら下がってたの？
Whoa, he's frozen!
わー 冷え冷え
星って冷たいんじゃの
Stars are real cold, huh?
No, Stella. It's because he's a pseudo-star.
違うよ ステラちゃん
偽物だから冷たいんだよ
Ah, you're right!
そうじゃったばい
お 俺のマスク
My mask!
All that brutality changed the mask's color...
あまりの酷使に
マスクの色がくすんじゃってるわね
ふふー あらあら マスクを取ったら
ただの変態さんね
Ah, you're just another pervert without the mask.
かっ 体むちゃくちゃ痛いし
寒いんですけどー
I-I'm freezing cold and m-my
body hurts all over...
Here.
これで暖をとるがいい
They should warm you up.
Back off!
温まるかー！
Oh, how selfish of you.
まあ なんて傲慢な
それに本当に辛かったのは
ロープさんのほうよ
Please understand, Mr. Rope here
works harder than any of you.
Thank Mr. Rope for holding up
a fat little piggy like you,
僕みたいなブタを縛って下さって
ありがとうってロープさんに感謝し
and apologize to the cookies for your impudence.
あなたが無下にしたクッキーに
ひざまずきなさいな
どあー まだ続くのそれ！
Is she still doing this?!
Why don't you cut him some slack, Maria?
もう許してやってもいいのではないか？
マリア
Shut it, cookie slave.
お黙り クッキーのしもべ
Well? Hurry up and apologize
for your miserable existence!
さあ 心を込めて
自分の存在を謝りなさい
Tell the cookies you're sorry!
クッキーに謝らんかい
お お前らも
You, too?!
He's running away!
逃げたぞ
Heeey!
こらー！
My mask smells like another guy...
マスクから他人のにおいがする
No one here, not even Ko, has realized
they're perfectly safe?
まさか助かったことを
行も住人たちもまだ知らないのか
ということは計画を食い止めたのは
行ではないのか
Which means Ko didn't thwart
my plans. Then... who?
一体…
はあ はあ ぐっは はあ…
Rec, why are you running away?
まあリクくん 逃げるつもり？
Stop! Ah, I have to do something—
ふあっ あの ちょっと用があって
こっちだリクくん 白線をたどって
Over here, Rec!
Just follow the white li—
Get outta my way!
邪魔！ 邪魔ですって！
おああー！
No. It was my mistake to think
he could ever overpower me.
いや
あれに私を出し抜く力があるなどと
考えたほうが どうかしていたか
He can't even confront me over the phone.
私に電話越しの抗議すらできん男だ
This is a waste of time. I'll have Shimazaki
lead the rest of the investigation.
時間の無駄だ
帰って後は島崎に探らせるか
Hey, you leaving? What about your pants?
おい 帰るのか？ ズボンはどうする？
Do what you want with them.
I don't have time for this.
君の好きにしたまえ 私は忙しいのでね
失礼する
Goodbye.
おおーっ ズボンが歌っているぞ
Your pants are singing!
That ringtone—
着信音だ
Can I really keep them?
おお 本当にこれ好きにしていいのか？
I haven't heard that ringtone
since I first set it up.
設定したきり
一度も鳴らなかったメロディー
Is that your phone ringing?
Don't you wanna answer it?
電話なのか？ 出ないとダメなんじゃ…
I couldn't possibly answer the phone
that you retrieved for me.
君に取ってもらった電話に
出るわけにはいかん
Go ahead and answer it.
Frankly, he's not worth my time.
君が出るといい
元より私の時間をそいつにはやれん
いいのか？
You sure?
I'm leaving now.
では失敬
ふわふわとした温かく優しかったものが
It may feel soft, warm, and inviting.
あ あった
Found it!
But like cotton soaked in water,
綿が水を吸うように
これからどんどん重くなる
it will grow heavier the longer you carry it,
立っていられなくなるほどに
until you can no longer stand.
Can you bear it until the very end?
お前はそれを
最後まで持っていられるか？
Try it, if you will!
やれるものなら やってみるがいい！
私にできなかった事を
If you think...
you can succeed where I failed.
お前にできるというのなら
あの  署まで…
Um, could you—
No!
Don't even finish that thought.
phone call.
"
One
みなまで言うな
Chapter 99: "Conclusions"
ほっ ここか？
Here? No... right here?
いや違う　こ ここか？
ダメだ！
出方 教えてもらえばよかったな
Stupid! I should've asked him how to answer it!
F-Father?
と 父さん…？
あ 出てくれてありがとうございます
Thanks for answering your phone.
Oh, don't hang up! No, I mean—
ああ 切らないでくださいね
あ あ いや ダメだ…
もうおー
I'm just gonna come out and say it.
単刀直入に言いますから
ああ どうやって話せば…
ああ リクを捜さないと
Ah, how do I? I need to find Rec!
Even... even if I have to leave
because of what happened here,
俺は今回の事で橋の下に
いられなくなっても
それでも…
ずっとニノさんと一緒にいます！
I'm going to stand by Nino forever!
だ だから…
So... what you're doing is pointless!
無駄ですからね　何したって
は ああ…！
No matter what—
俺だって！
I—
Sure.
そうだな…
Let's stay together forever.
ずっと… 一緒にいような
Ni—
Nino... how—
ニノさん なんで？
Oh, Rec! Hey, I don't know
おおリク！ なあ
携帯電話の出方が分からない…
how to answer this cell pho—
You already did.
いや… 出れてますよ
ってその携帯 誰の？
Whose phone is— Why are
these phones connected?
なんでこれと つながってるんですか？
Oh, you're right.
おう 本当だ
But I just—
だって俺今…
Some guy was walking by and gave it to me.
通りすがりのおじさんがくれたんだ
はいてたズボンごとくれたんだぞ
He gave me his pants, too.
それただの変態じゃないですか？
He sounds like some kind of freak!
Thirty minutes later, Ko receives
a call from the Ministry of Land
この30分後 国交省からの電話で
リクは橋の下の工事の中止を知る
telling him the construction
plans have been canceled.
And...
そして…
ふっ もう気は済んだかね？
Are you happy now?
How can you be so arrogant,
sitting there in your underwear?!
なんでそんなに偉そうなんだ
パンツなのに！
Rec's father is released an hour later.
Shimazaki comes to pick him up.
リクの父が釈放されるのは
島崎が迎えに来る この１時間後でだった
Chapter 100: "Arakawa Qwik-Skit Challenge"
Okay, is everyone ready?
It's time for impression training!
Um, excuse me!
'Sup?
I... don't know how to do any impressions.
あの日夕暮れ
Fear not, Rec. That's what
the training session is for.
Besides, all I brought is materials for beginners.
Beginners?
Yup. Like imitating familiar animals and stuff.
愛のカケラ 探すたびに
Oh, well in that case...
Great! Then why don't you go first, Rec?
いつも何故か 寂しくなる
Huh? Are you serious?
Relax, Rec. Relax!
Sure...
Don't think about it, Rec.
もう行かなくちゃ
Just pay attention to the topic the Chief
gives you, then let your heart guide you.
この空泣き出す前に
Okay! So... topic, please.
All right... I shouldn't have any problem
with simple animal sounds.
サカサマになって
君の事探して
Topic:
Kanchil
Kan—
いつまでも僕らは
—chil
Kanchil
WHAT THE HELL'S THAT?!
たどり着けないまま
There it is—kanchil!
橋の下に立って
Rec! Do a kanchil!
流れる渦に在って
C'mon, kanchil!
Hey hey, Kanchil! Hey hey, Rec!
いつまでも僕らは
その答え探して
Umm... kan...
Kanchil! Also known as the Java Mouse-deer!
Neither of those are helpful!
Don't think about it! Follow your heart!
Huh? Uh... okay!
The sound of a kanchil... here I go!
Ahh... he just doesn't have the chops for improv.
ようし 準備はいいかな？
モノマネの特訓始めるぞー！
あの… すいません！
なんだ？
俺… モノマネなんて
一つもできないんですけど
A giant robot appears in a
peaceful riverside community!
The bridge is destroyed!
So are everyone's houses!
心配するなリク そのための特訓だ
Next time, on 13 BRIDGE!
Red Venusian!
それに今回は
初歩的なお題ばかり用意してある
Blue Venusian!
Yellow Venusian!
Finally, a real
preview-ish preview!
初歩的な？
Wait, was that all
just sleep talk?!
そ 身近な動物の鳴き真似とかだ
Illustration: Yana Toboso
ああ それだったら
よし じゃあリクからやってみるか
えっ いきなり
リクくん リラックス リラックス
あ はい
リク 何も考えるな
村長から出たお題を
心のままに演じるんだ
はい！
お題 お願いします
よし 身近な動物の鳴き真似くらい
簡単にできる
お題 「コン・チェオ」
って何それー！
きたよ コン・チェオ
うん リク！ コン・チェオだ！
カモーン！ コン・チェオ！
へいへい コン・チェオ
へいへい リクー！
え ええと コ コン…
コン・チェオ！
またの名をジャワマメジカだ！
どっちにしろ知らねえ！
考えるなリク！ 心のままにだ！
へ あ はい えーと
じゃあ コン・チェオの鳴き声…
いきまーす
ああー あいつモノマネの才能ねえなあ
あーあ
平和な荒川河川敷に突如現れた
巨大ロボット
橋が みんなの家が破壊され尽くす！
次回 「13 BRIDGE」
赤金星人 青金星人 黄金星人
ここにきて急に予告っぽい予告きたー！
って今の全部寝言？